<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GraphQL on Howdy,Kloudy!</title>
    <link>/tags/graphql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GraphQL on Howdy,Kloudy!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/graphql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the PowerShell GitLab Utility Module</title>
      <link>/blog/introducing-the-powershell-gitlab-utility-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introducing-the-powershell-gitlab-utility-module/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Harnessing GitLab with PowerShell: Introducing the PowerShell.GitLab.Utility Module
In the evolving landscape of DevOps and CI/CD, automating and streamlining operations is invaluable. GitLab, a web-based DevOps lifecycle tool, provides a comprehensive platform for software development, from project planning and source code management to CI/CD, monitoring, and security. To enhance the interaction with GitLab through automation, the PowerShell.GitLab.Utility modules have emerged as a significant advancement.
What is PowerShell.GitLab.Utility? PowerShell.GitLab.Utility is a PowerShell module designed to interface with GitLab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the GitLab GraphQL API in PowerShell</title>
      <link>/blog/using-the-gitlab-graphql-api-in-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 11:20:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/using-the-gitlab-graphql-api-in-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GraphQL is a revolutionary query language and runtime for API interactions in web development. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t just transform how we request and manage data—it reshapes the entire API landscape. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll unveil the power of GitLab GraphQL API, exploring how it offers a comprehensive and user-friendly approach to data manipulation and API evolution.
At its core, GraphQL serves as a versatile tool for querying APIs and orchestrating data retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
